Guide to the Wesleyan Addresses to Freshmen Collection, 1980 - 1989
Wesleyan Addresses to Freshmen Collection, 1980 - 1989
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University.
2006-36
0.2
1
During the 1980s, a Wesleyan faculty member was asked to deliver an address to the incoming freshman class each year. These addesses contained advice and wisdom about the students' upcoming lives at Wesleyan University. These addresses were transcribed and printed by Wesleyan.
These addresses were made to incoming students at the beginning of the academic year throughout the 1980s.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Given by Karl Scheibe, June 2006.
Historical Note
During the 1980s, a Wesleyan faculty member was asked to deliver an address to the incoming freshman class each year. These addesses contained advice and wisdom about the students' upcoming lives at Wesleyan University. These addresses were transcribed and printed by Wesleyan.
Collection Overview
These addresses were made to incoming students at the beginning of the academic year throughout the 1980s.
Collection Arrangement
Items are arranged chronologically.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Konstan, David.; Hawkins, Sherman.; Rosenbaum, R. A. (Robert A.); Hanson, Earl D.; Arnold, Herbert A.; Allewell, Norma.; Wood, Robert Coldwell, 1923-; Kiefer, Barry I.; Butler, Jeffrey.; Winston, Krishna.; Speeches, addresses, etc., American.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Faculty.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Wesleyan Addresses
  - The Liberal Education by David Konstan, 28 August 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Liberal Education by Sherman Hawkins, 27 August 1981 (Folder 2)
  - Another Vicious Versus by Robert A. Rosenbaum, 26 August 1982 (Folder 3)
  - Course Credits=Education: Making that Formula Work by Earl D. Hanson, 26 August 1983 (Folder 4)
  - Liberal Learning, Radical Criticism and Moral Responsibility; or Adam: the First Liberal Learner by Herbert A. Arnold, 30 August 1984 (Folder 5)
  - The Freedom of Necessity by Norma Allewell, 29 August 1985 (Folder 6)
  - Politics: the Core Curriculum by Robert Wood, 28 August 1986 (Folder 7)
  - The Evolution of a Liberal Education by Barry Kiefer, 3 September 1987 (Folder 8)
  - The Who, Me? Question and a College Education by Jeffrey Butler, 1 September 1988 (Folder 9)
  - Do Worry, But Be Happy! by Krishna Winston, 31 August 1989 (Folder 10)